Guide to the Edwin Warriner Papers and Photographs, 1790-1958 1977.255
Brooklyn Historical Society
Edwin Warriner papers and photographs
1790-1958
1860-1900
Brooklyn Historical Society
Methodist Episcopal Church. New York East Conference
Warriner, Edwin
1977.255
6.25 Linear Feet in 15 manuscript boxes and 3 photograph boxes
The bulk of the Edwin Warriner (1839-1898) papers and photographs includes the research notes and related materials gathered during the last decades of the nineteenth century in preparation for a planned, but never completed, encyclopedia of Methodism on Long Island, New York. Warriner's files concern Methodist ministers, churches, circuits, and locales throughout Long Island. The collection includes correspondence, transcriptions, draft manuscript entries, clippings, and photographs, such as cabinet cards, cartes-de-visite, and tintypes. Warriner's files also include some original documents dating from as early as 1791. The collection also includes printed material dating from the twentieth century that was added to the Warriner files after his death in 1898.This material consists mostly of special anniversary publications and other such documents that include historical notes on various Methodist churches.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in three series:
The collection is organized in the following three series:
Missing Title
Notes and Ephemera
Photographs and Other Images
Later Additions to the Collection
Biographical / Historical
Edwin Warriner was born on January 19, 1839, in Ellisburg, NY. He was born into a religious family; his father, Solomon J. Warriner, was a farmer and local Methodist preacher. By the time he was fifteen, Warriner was teaching public school and had obtained a license to be a Methodist preacher. He went on to study theology at the Biblical Institute of Concord, New Hampshire, from which he graduated in 1861. Warriner then began his career in the ministry in South Meriden, Connecticut. At the beginning of the Civil War, a regiment of soldiers was garrisoned there and he began to minister to them. Warriner was appointed as chaplain to the regiment and traveled with them for three years during the war. Afterwards, he settled in Brooklyn as a Methodist minister.
By 1880, Warriner was Secretary of the New York East Conference Historical Society. His two published books, The Old Sands Street Methodist Episcopal Church of Brooklyn, NY, published in 1885, and The Warriner Family of New England Origin, a history of his family from 1628 to 1898, show his passion for both history and genealogy. Warriner died in 1898, shortly after finishing the Warriner Family manuscript, which was published a year later. Warriner's purpose in collecting the documents forming most of this collection was to write an encyclopedia of Methodism on Long Island. He died before producing a written manuscript based on his research. The bulk of the letters in this collection, in which Warriner asks for information about a certain church or reverend, dates from the 1870s-1890s, indicating that he had been collecting information about Methodism on Long Island for the last 30 years of his life.
Conditions Governing Access
The donor of the collection restricted its use to research in biography and church history. Nonetheless, to ensure against unwarranted denial of access to the collection, Brooklyn Historical Society interprets the scope of these subject areas broadly.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In 1955, the collection was initially placed in "permanent custody" with the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society) by the New York East Annual Conference of the Methodist Church, through Reverend Robert H. Dolliver, Secretary of the Methodist Historical Society in the City of New York. Extant records suggest that, in 1958, the Conference agreed to change the status of the collection, making it a gift to the Brooklyn Historical Society.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the collection includes the research notes and related materials gathered by Reverend Edwin Warriner during the last decades of the nineteenth century in preparation for a planned, but never completed, encyclopedia of Methodism on Long Island, New York. Warriner's handwritten notes concern Methodist ministers, churches, circuits, and locales throughout Long Island. African Methodist Episcopal (AME), German and Norwegian churches are included. Warriner's files include correspondence in response to his inquiries for information; transcriptions of church records, histories and other documents; draft manuscript entries; newspaper clippings; and photographs, such as cabinet cards, cartes-de-visite, and tintypes. Warriner's files also include some original documents dating from as early as 1791.
The collection also includes printed material dating from the twentieth century that was added to the Warriner files by the Methodist Historical Society and donated with the collection to the Long Island Historical Society (now Brooklyn Historical Society). This material consists mostly of special anniversary publications and other such documents that include historical notes on various Methodist churches.
Other Finding Aids
There is a record for the Edwin Warriner papers and photographs collection in PastPerfect, Brooklyn Historical Society's image database. That record is indexed with the names associated with images found in Series 2 of the collection. However, no images from the collection can be viewed in Pastperfect.
Related Materials
Brooklyn Historical Society holds archival material concerning various Methodist churches:
Methodist Episcopal Church in Brooklyn quarterly conference minutes, 1824-1834 (call number 1973.294).
Good Ground Methodist Episcopal Church records, 1865-1867, including subscription lists, receipts, and accounts for the building fund (call number 1977.427).
An unidentified Methodist minister's marriage and baptism record book, 1844-1892 (call number 1978.050).
Sands Street Methodist Episcopal Church class register (one) and church programs (three), 1850-94 (call number 1985.086).
Brooklyn Church Society of the Methodist Episcopal Church annual reports, 1883-1928 (call number 1985.095). The reports include charters, constitutions and bylaws, listings of officers and committees, listings of managers elected by each member church, listings of individual members, details regarding the value of member churches' properties and indebtedness, treasurer's reports, receipts of member church collections, annual meeting summaries, historical notes on member churches, and officiaries of member churches.
Methodist Churches of Brooklyn collection, 1856-1978 (call number 1986.027). The collection contains materials relating to sixteen Methodist churches located in Brooklyn and includes church histories, yearbooks, bulletins, invitations, directories, programs, and one scrapbook.
Hanson Place Central Methodist Church publications, 1909-75 (call number ARC.171). The collection is primarily comprised of The Messenger, a newsletter issued from 1958 to 1975.
Methodist Church |z United States |x Clergy |v Biography; Methodist Church |z United States |x History; Methodist Episcopal Church |z New York (State) |z Queens County; Souvenir programs; Clergy |z New York (State) |z Queens County; Commemoratives; Kings County (N.Y.) |x Church history; Long Island (N.Y.) -- Church history; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history; Clergy |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Methodist Episcopal Church |z New York (State) |z Long Island; Methodist Episcopal Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Church anniversaries |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Methodists, German |z New York (State) |z Kings County; African American churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Queens County (N.Y.) |x Church history; Methodist Church |x Clergy; Clergy -- New York (State) -- Long Island; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; African American churches -- New York (State) -- Long Island; Research notes; Tintypes (prints); Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Cabinet photographs; Methodist Episcopal Church. New York East Conference
- 1. Notes and Ephemera, 1791-1940; 5.42 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes Warriner's handwritten notes on Methodist ministers, churches, circuits, and locales throughout Long Island, New York. African Methodist Episcopal (AME), German and Norwegian churches are included.
  The extent of material concerning each subject is uneven. In many instances, a subject file contains only minor notations or only a cross-reference to another subject file where relevant material can be found. Other files contain more extensive materials. Overall, the series includes correspondence responding to Warriner's inquiries for information; research notes; Warriner's transcriptions of church records, histories, and other documents; draft entries, likely for the intended encyclopedia; newspaper clippings, including published images and death notices; and programs and similar ephemera.
  The bulk of these documents date from the 1880s and the years immediately prior and subsequent. Although the notes date from the late nineteenth century, the date range of transcriptions and the subject matter spans the century from the late eighteenth to late nineteenth century. Also, there are a few original documents from as early as 1791, including two appointments signed by Francis Asbury and church building subscription books, among other items. These original documents are noted in the container list.
  Arrangement
  The series is in Warriner's original order, which is alphabetical by subject. Warriner assigned a numeric sequencing to the subjects; where known, this number is indicated in the container list in parentheses after the subject name.
  Because the bulk of the documents date from the 1880s, and many files contain undated material, a date range is not noted for each file. Where an original document from a period earlier than Warriner's research was identified during processing, that is noted in the container list.
  - Abbot, Alvin Van Rensselaer (A.V.R.) (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Benjamin (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Bennet (image included) (2A) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abbott, Ira (3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abele, George (4) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abrahams, Smith (4A) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Benjamin (5) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Afflerbach, Christian (6) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africanus, Edward (6A) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen, George (7) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alvord, E.P. (7-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amagansett (8) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amerman, Oliver V. (9) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amityville African M. E. Church (10) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amityville M. E. Church (Huntington South Church) (12) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amityville Circuit (12A) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amityville North Church (13) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amos, A. S. (13A) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anderson, Abram (13B) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anderson, Andrew J. (13C) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anderson, George H. (14) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Andrews, Edward G. (image included) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Andrus, Luman (17) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appointment of Preachers to the African M. E. Zion Church (18A) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Armitage, Thomas (21) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armstrong, John (22) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armstrong, Noble (23) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armstrong, William P. (24) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arnold, Smith (25) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aston, Henry (26) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Astoria German M. E. Mission (26-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Astoria M. E. Church (27) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Astoria Trinity M. E. Church (27A) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Atlanticville M. E. Church (28) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Atlanticville M. E. Church, see Seaford (28A) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Authorities, consulted and quoted within works (29) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Babylon and Islip Circuit (1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Babylon M. E. Church (1-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bachman, Charles (2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bailey, William (2-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baird, Joseph (3) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baker, Henry (3-1/4) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baker, Stephen (4) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baker, S. (4-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baldwins, formerly Hicks Neck (5) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baldwins Meth. Prot. Church (5-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baldwinsville and Freeport Circuit (6) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bangs, Herman (7) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bangs, William H. (9) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bangs, William M. (10) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barber, William B (11) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barnhart, Isaiah C (12) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barnhart, John Wesley (13) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bartlett, Horace (14) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bartlett, Phillip (15) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bass, Job G. (16) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bates, Edmond (17) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Battersby, Charles (17-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bayport (18) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bay Ridge or New Utrecht Circuit (19) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bay Ridge M. E. Church (20) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bay Shore African M. E. Church (20A) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bay Shore Congregational Meth. Church (20C) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bayville, formerly Oak Neck (22) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Beach, Anson F. (23) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Beach, John Wesley (24) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Beach, Theodore C. (25) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Beach, Thomas (26) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Beale, C. H. (27) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Beiler, Samuel L. (27-2/3) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Beale, W. (27A) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bedell, Moses (27B) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bell, James J. (28) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bele, Fred (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bellmore, formerly New Bridge (28A) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bellport African M. E. Zion. Church (29) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Belmont, Abraham (30A) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bennett, J. H. (31) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bethel (or Baldwins) and Freeport Circuit (32) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bethel M. E. Church, see Baldwins (33) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bethel, Thomas W. (34) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bethpage, see Farmingdale (35) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bigelow, Noah (36) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bile, F. W. (37) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Birch, James (37A) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Blagborne, William (38) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blake, Edwin (39) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blakeman, Wilbur (40) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blatz, H. (41) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blinn, Christian (42) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bonn, Frederick (43-1/2) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Boardman, Richard (43-1/4) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Blue Point (43) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Boole, William H. (45) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Booth, Albert (46) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Booth, John F. (47) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bosworth (47A) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bottome, Francis (48) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bouton, James David (49) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bovard, Melville (49A) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowdish, Arvine (50) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowdish, Charles G. (51) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowdish, Wellesley W. (52) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowen, Josiah (53) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowen, Borden P. (54) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Boyd, James (55) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Boyd, John (56) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Brainard, Cephas (57) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bray, James M. (58) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bray, Spencer H. (59) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Breckenridge, John S. (60) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brenner, William F. (61) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brockmeyer, C. (61-1/4) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Breslan (German) (62) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bridge Hampton M. E. Church (63) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brien, John (64) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brookfield, with East Manor (65) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brookhaven and Bellport Circuit (66) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brookhaven, formerly Fire Place (67) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brookville (67-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brower, Calvin L. (68) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Charles S. (image included) (69) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brown, David (70) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Ebenezer (71) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Frederick (72) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown, George (73) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Oliver E. (74) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Paul R. (75) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brown, William (76) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brundage, Isaac (77) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brush, Jacob (78) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brushy Plains, see East Meadow (79) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Buck, Charles H. (80) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buck, David (80A) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buckelen, Joshua R. (81) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Buckley, James M. (image included) (82) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Buckram, see Locust Valley (83) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Buell, E. George (84) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Buell, Marcus D. (85) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Buhre, Ernst H. (86) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bull, Mitchell B. (87) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Burch, Joshua (87A) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Burch, Thomas (88) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Burch, Thomas H. (89) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Burnes, Harvey E. (89A) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Burns, Arthur M. (90) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Burrows, Albert S. (91) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Burrows, Joshua L. (92) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Burt, William (92-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Burton, Henry (93) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bushnell, Samuel (94) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bushwick, see Brooklyn (95) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Butler, Thomas (96) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Byrn, M. Lafayette (97) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brooklyn and East New York Mission (1) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn and Long Island Preachers Meeting (1A) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn and New Utrecht Circuit (2) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn: Asbury African M. E. Church (3) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn: Asbury M. E. Church (4) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn: Andrews M. E. Church, formerly Cypress Hills (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn: Atlantic Dock, see Williams Street (5) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn: Bedford Ave Meth. Prot. Church (5-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn: Bethel Ship (Scandinavian) (7) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn: Bethel Ship Chapel (8) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn: Bridge Street African M. E. Church (9) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn: Broadway M. E. Mission (10) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn, Broadway Mission, the Second (11) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn Circuit African M. E. Church (12) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn Circuit M. E. Church (13) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn M. E. Mission (14) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn: Bushwick Ave. (14-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn: Butler Street M. E. Mission (15) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn: Carlton Ave M. E. Church (16) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn: Carroll Park M. E. Church (17) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn: Cedar Street M. E. Church (18) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn: Central M. E. Church (19) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn Church Society (19A) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn (E.D.) City Mission (21) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn: Cook Street M. E. Church (22) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn: Cross Road M. E. Church (22B) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn: Dean Street, see Hanson Place (23) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn: DeKalb Ave M. E. Church (image only) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn: E.D. African M. E. Zion Church (27A) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Brooklyn: Eighteenth St M. E. Church (28) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Brooklyn: Embury M. E. Church (29) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Brooklyn: First Bethel African M. E. Church (30) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brooklyn: First Congregational Meth Church (31) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brooklyn: First Free Meth. Church (32) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brooklyn: First M. E. Church - Greenpoint (image included) (32A) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brooklyn: First Meth. Prot. Church (33) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn: First Place M. E. Church (33A) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn: Fleet Street African M. E. Church (33C) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn: First Primitive Meth Church (33B) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn: Fleet Street M. E, Church (34) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Brooklyn: Forty Fourth St. M. E. Church (35) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn: Fourth Primitive Meth Church (35-3/4) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn: Fourth Ave, formerly 44th St Church (35A) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn: Fourth Meth. Prot. Church (35B) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn: Fourth St. Meth. Prot. Church (36) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brooklyn: Francis M. E. Church (37) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Brooklyn: Franklin Ave M. E. Church (37A) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Brooklyn: Free Union Meth. Church E.D. (African) (38) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Brooklyn: Fulton Street (38-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Brooklyn: Gates Ave M. E. Church (39) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Brooklyn: Goodsell Mission (39-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Brooklyn: German Mission (41) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Brooklyn: Goodsell Sunday School Mission (41A) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Brooklyn: Gothic, see Dowers St (42) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brooklyn: Grace Church, formerly 7th Ave (42-1/4) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brooklyn: Graham Ave Meth Prot Church (43) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brooklyn: Grand St. Meth Prot Church (43-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brooklyn: Greene Ave Church (image only) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Brooklyn: Greenpoint First Church (45) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Brooklyn: Greenpoint Tabernacle (46) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Brooklyn: Hanson Place M. E. Church (47) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Brooklyn: Hatfield M. E. Mission (48) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Brooklyn: Harrison Ave German M. E. Mission (49) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Brooklyn: Hidding M. E. Mission (50) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Brooklyn: Hicks St. M. E. Church (51) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Brooklyn: Janes M. E. Church (51A) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Brooklyn: Johnson St M. E. Church (52) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Brooklyn: Kosciusco St M. E. Church (52-1/2) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brooklyn: Ladies Home M. E. Mission (53) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brooklyn: Leonard St M. E. Church (E.D.) (54) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brooklyn: Local Preachers Association (54A) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brooklyn: Lorimar St German M. E. Church (55) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brooklyn: Lutheran Methodist (56) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Brooklyn: Mariners M. E. Church (57) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Brooklyn: Mead Memorial Church (57A) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Brooklyn: Methodist Home for the Aged (57B) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Brooklyn: Methodist Episcopal Hospital (57C) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn: Methodist Hospital (57D) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn: Missionary Training Institute (57E) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn: Mt. Zion African Prot Meth Church (58) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn: Nathan Bangs M. E. Church (59) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn: New York Ave M. E. Church (61) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn: North Fifth St M. E. Church (62) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn: Norwegian Bethel (62A) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn: Norwegian Mission M. E. Church (62B) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn: Nostrand Ave M. E. Church (63) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn: Orchard M. E. Mission (64) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn: Orchard Primitive Meth Church (64-1/2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn: Pacific St M. E. Church (65) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn: Park Ave M. E. Mission (66) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn: Park Ave Primitive Meth. Church (67) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn: Poplar St African M. E. Church (67-1/2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn: Powers St M. E. Church (68) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn: Protestant Meth Church (69) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn: Remsen St Meth Prot Church (71) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn: Reid Ave M. E. Church (71-1/4) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn: Ridgewood Chapel (71-1/3) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn: Russell Place M. E. Church (71-1/2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn: St John's M. E. Church (72) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn: St Paul's M. E. Church (72B) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn: St Luke's M. E. Church (72A) (Box 3, Folder 12)